GURJAPPAN SINGH Software Engineer

email: gurjappan@gmail.com phone #: +91-9780676707 city: Chandigarh, India

ABOUT ME

Full stack developer **javascript** developer with over 7 years of experience. Adept in **advanced React, Typescript, NodeJS**. I have used **AWS** services extensively through-out my experience and have a good hold on **serverless architecture** as well. I love reviewing code and getting my code reviewed. Experienced in TDD, Agile methods, git and planning out a structured solution for every problem.

SKILLS

- Frontend: React, Redux, Typescript, Google-maps, SVG objects, CSS
- Designing: MaterialUI, Figma, Bootstrap
- Backend: NestJS, ExpressJS, Python(flask),
- Cloud: AWS (cognito, lambdas, ec2, fargate etc)
- Testing: Jest, pally for accessibilty testing, TDD
- Scripting: shell scripting, python
- Databases: DynamoDB, MongoDB, MySQL.
- Blockchain: Solidity, EtherJs, Infura

WORK EXPERIENCES

• SOFTWARE ENGINEER

April 2022 - January 2023 | Cruise Automation / Procloz (Contractor)

- Worked with a San Francisco based enterprise startup that has raised \$15b in the autonomous car sector. One of the most active organisations working towards building autonomous vehicles as cabs.
- Worked on the Customer support section of the company which is first point of human interaction for all the riders. A button from the car connects a specialist using the HALO app.
- Used NestJS on the backend and React on the Frontend. Twilio for handling conferences. JEST for testing every feature since interacting with an actual vehicle while developing is hard. Storybook/Storycap for building/Testing UI components. Mapbox for showing the vehicles live location and other destination related features.
- SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER
 December 2021 April 2022 | Nagarro Software
 - Worked for a Fortune 500 client in Retail as a full stack developer for creating features for the rebuttal and fines wing of the company.
 - Used Javascript on the front-end as well as the backend to contribute to the project.

WORK EXPERIENCES

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2019 - November 2021 | Trantor software

- Creating the front-end for a white-labeled enterprize level application for a leading insurance domain client
- Setting everything from scratch, using react, typescript, and redux
- Follow test driven developement with a domain driven architecture. Use pally for automated testing. Working with Mockups on Figma for different white label clients.
- Using Docker for containerizing the application, setup bitbucket pipelines.
- Work extensively with arch team in creating OAS v3 specs using stoplight.
- SOFTWARE ENGINEER

January 2017 - November 2019 | BigBerry Media

- Create an application to manage call centers
- Using Python/Flask to build a backend for handling calls. Using Codelgniter to render the app.
- Setting up Asterisk which is a command line tool governing PBX systems for Linux based operating systems.
- Create a JavaScript based softphone using Sockets
- Design using HTML CSS, Bootstrap

OTHER PROJECTS / FREELANCE

- Volt AI (a ML powered start up providing smart security systems)
- Haulshare (worked full-stack for the app from scratch using expressJS on the backend and React w/ NextJS on the frontend.)
- Tenkys.ai (worked on d3js, high charts in building different graphs and charts)
- OVRT (Worked on a blockchain related startup for creating a simple smart contract for minting NFTs) Using EthersJS on the front-end with React to work with it.
- Experience in creating web scrappers and website automation using selenium, cypress, phantomJS, and beautifulSoup
- I have successfully installed Arch Linux and use it on a daily basis :D

EDUCATION

2011 - 2015 | CHANDIGARH ENGINEERING COLLEGE

Bachelor in Technology, Computer Science